Guide to the Ester Hernandez Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Artist's Files, Series 6; 14 linear ft.
  - General, Subseries 6.1
    - Islas, Arturo. The Rain God (Alexanandrain Press, Palo Alto, CA 1984).Inscription and note by Islas. (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - JiHonrilo, Avotcja, et al. Third World Women, Third World Communications, SF, 1972: compilation of essays and writings, inscription by Avotcja. (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Jimenez, Flaco: photographs, slides, Cinco de Mayo, Berkeley, CA, 1987 (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - La Marr, Jean: correspondence, exhibition announcement; photographs, slides, 1986[?]-1992 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Las Mujeres Muralistas: Academic essays, news articles, slides, miscellaneous information. (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Limon, Leo: correspondence (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Lippard, Lucy: correspondence (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Lopez, Yolanda: corespondence, exhibition announcements, benefit announcements, miscellaneous material, slides (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Magu: paper cutouts (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Mali, Wu: Art Taiwan brochure, featuring works of Mali (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Martinez, Alma: correspondence (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Mirikitani, Janice. Shedding Silence (Celestial Arts, Berkeley, CA, 1987). Inscription by author. (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Montoya, Malaquias: correspondence, exhibit annnouncement (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Montoya, Malaquias: exhibition booklet, San Francisco Art Institute, 1997 (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Moraga, Cherrie: "Heroes and Saints "production for Brava: grant application, theater programs, news articles, miscellaneous materials (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Moraga, Cherrie (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Moreno, Renee: personal information, correspondence from 1990s, photographs, slides. (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - Moreno, Renee: writings (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Munoz, Celia: correspondence, photograph (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Munoz, Manuel. Greetings From Ice Country, Chicano Chap Book #19, 1998 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Ortiz Taylor, Shiela, and Sandra. Imaginary Parents: A Family Autobiography, University of New Mexico Press, Albuquerque, NM (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Paquita la del Barrio: news article on Mexican singer; photographs, taken at her nightclub, Mexico, DF, 1993 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Paz, Suni: lyrics or verse, autographed [Chilean songwriter, singer, poet], ca. 1978 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Perez, Laura: correspondence, copies of ms articles/essays, permission forms, miscellaneous material (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Poniatowski, Elena: "Juchitan, a Town of Women: the Man With the Sweet Penis," reprint (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Quirarte, Jacinto: request for information (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Rebollado, Tey Diana: correspondence, book covers, University of Arizona Press catalog, Spring 1995 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Rice-Trujillo, Celia: photographs, 1985, 1995 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - Rodriguez, Lily "Isis": correspondence, exhibition announcement, photographs, miscellaneous material. (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - Rodriguez, Patricia: photographs, slides, course outline, exhibition announcement, miscellaneous material. (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - Roth, Moira: correspondence, invitations, miscellaneous material. (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - Sanchez-Duarte, Cecelia: correspondence, miscellaneous material (Box 58, Folder 14)
    - Shaw, Rebecca Salome: correspondence, text of slide presentation (Box 58, Folder 15)
    - Solis, Diana: photographs, "Chicago, Halsted Street Bus 'Las Palomas;'" "Michoacan, Mexico." (Box 58, Folder 16)
    - Soto, Gary: correspondence, bills of sale, series of chapbooks edited by Soto. (Box 58, Folder 17)
    - Tan, Amy: correspondence, miscellaneous material (Box 58, Folder 18)
    - Teresita la Campesina [Alberto Gonzalez Nevares]: performance announcements, photographs (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Teresita la Campesina [Alberto Gonzalez Nevares]: photographs,slides: San Francisco, 1985; Berkeley, 1997; San Francisco, Mission Dolores, 1997 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Trujillo, Carla: "La Virgen de Guadalupe and Her Re-construction in Chicana Lesbian Desire," academic paper, bill of sale (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Underwood, Consuelo: correspondence, exhbit announcement, news article (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Underwood, Consuelo Jimenez: Las Fuerzas de la Tierra, exhibition booklet, Museo de El Carmen, Teotihuacan, Mexico, 1993 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Underwood, Consuelo Jimenez: Fronteras de Anahuac, exhibition booklet, Museo Textil de Terrassa, Barcelona, Spain, 1995 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Valdez, Luis: news article (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Valdez, Patsi (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Yampolsky, Mariana: correspondence, exhbit announcement, news articles, photographs, slides, miscellaneous materials (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Ybanez, Terri: correspondence (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Ybarra-Frausto, Tomas: "A History of Chicano Art" news article, miscellaneous material, photographs (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous slides (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - Astrid Hadad, Subseries 6.2
    - At Stanford University, September, 1988 (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - Ester's visit to Mexico, D.F., 1996 (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - Cabaret de la Luna, 1992 (Box 59, Folder 16)
    - Mexican Fine Arts Center, Chicago, Ill, 1994 (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - Press packet, ca. 1998 (Box 59, Folder 18)
    - Stanford University, Flor y Canto, 1999 (Box 59, Folder 19)
    - Receipt for cassettes, ca. 1996 (Box 59, Folder 20)
    - Sibila De Vila, 1996 (Box 59, Folder 21)
    - Prototype CD cover, 1999 (Box 59, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous emails, 1999 (Box 59, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous slides, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 24)
    - Astrid Hadad en "Corazon Sangrante," Ximena Cuevas, director, Mexico City; Astrid Hadad Y Los Tarzanes en "Heavy Nopal," Mexico: VHS videocassette, 6/15/1905 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Sor Juana Festival, Mexican Fine Arts Center Museum, Chicago, unedited, Tape #1, VHS videocassette, 11/2/1994 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Sor Juana Festival, Mexican Fine Arts Center Museum, Chicago, unedited, Tape #2, VHS videocassette, 11/2/1994 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Astrid Hadad at Stanford: VHS videocassette, May, 1999 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Para Luis Ambrie: Cortes de Diferentes Shows: VHS videocassette, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Astrid Hadad: Video 8 videotape, 6/14/1905 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - El Personal: Concierto en vivo Guadalajara - el Hospicio Cabanas, February, 1987 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Astrid Hadad Live, ca. 1996 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Recorded phone messages, Astrid Hadad and Ester Hernandez, June, 1994 (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Recorded phone messages, Astrid Hadad and Ester Hernandez, 2/18/1994 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Ay!: Astrid Hadad y Los Tarzanes, Discos Cabaret, Musicomedia, audiocassette, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Ay!: Astrid Hadad y Los Tarzanes, Discos Cabaret, Musicomedia, compact disk (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Ay!: Astrid Hadad y Los Tarzanes, Nubenegra, compact disk, 1994 (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - Astrid's favorite music, taped for Ester Hernandez: Musica Mexicana, audio cassette (Box 60, Folder 14)
    - Astrid's favorite music, taped for Ester Hernandez: Pepe Gutierrez con Lucha Reyes, Laurita Rivas, Juanita Escoto, Sara Rodriguez, Ernesto Cortazar con Lucha Reyes, audio cassette (Box 60, Folder 15)
    - Astrid's favorite music, taped for Ester Hernandez: Sofia Alavarez, Olga Ramos, Hermanas Diaz Trio Tariacuri, audio cassette (Box 60, Folder 16)
    - Astrid's favorite music, taped for Ester Hernandez: Lucha Reyes, Sofia Alvarez, Olga Ramos, audio cassetee (Box 60, Folder 17)
    - Hadad, Astrid: photographs, slides (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Graciela Iturbide, Subseries 6.3
    - Iturbide, Graciela. En el Nombre del Padre, Ediciones Toledo, Mexico, 1993 (Box 61, Folder 2)
      Autographed and inscribed by author
    - Miscellaneous material (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous publications (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - La fotografia en Mexico, n.d.; Set of postcards (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Japanese photo award brochure, ca. 1990 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - "External Encounters, Internal Imagings," San Francisco Museum of Modern Art exhibit material, 1990 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Iturbide, Graciela: photographs, slides (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Lydia Mendoza, Subseries 6.4
    - Lydia Mendoza: photographs, slides (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Extra material: Photographs, photocopies of newspaper, magazine, and journal articles (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Lydia Mendoza: "The Spiritualist," a story told by Lydia to Ester Hernandez on Sept. 15., 1986. Handwritten notes and a typed out simple edit fill in the gaps left out of the notes. (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Lydia Mendoza: "Why My Sister is Called Maria de Jesus" a story told to Ester Hernandez by Lydia Mendoza, ca. 1986. Handwritten and printed notes with minor editing. (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Postcard from Lydia to Ester Hernandez - NY, 1988 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Lydia Mendoza: "Lydia Mendoza - Showtime," installation, list of materials and insurance value. (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Photos -performance at Posada de colores, Oakland, CA, 1985 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Lydia Mendoza: torn page from Houston telephone book, ca. 1987; photo of poster from Lydia's house, part of personal archive. (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Lydia Mendoza: handwritten letter regarding flight from Fresno, 1986; letter from Radio Bilingue to Lydia, 1986 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Lydia Mendoza: miscellaneous material regarding Lydia's stay at Ester Hernandez's house, ca. 1986 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Lydia Mendoza: price list, ca. 1986 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Lydia Mendoza: original sketch by Ester Hernandez, ca 1985 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Miscellaneous material: press release, Voices of Americas, Washington Square Church, NewYork, NY; slide, San Juan Bautista, Teatro Campesinos; La Voz de Esparanza 10/1999; wrapping paper with Lydia's Houston address. (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Straichwitz, Chris, and Nicolopulos, James. Lydia Mendoza: a Family Autobiography, Art Publico Press, University of Houston, TX. Inscribed by Chris Straichwitz and Lydia Mendoza. (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Letter from Lydia, 3/5/1985 (Box 62, Folder 13)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia's unmailed postcard to Jesus Chavez, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 14)
    - Lydia Mendoza: postcard from Lydia, from Santa Barbara, CA, 1986 (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Letter from Lydia, 10/15/1985 (Box 62, Folder 16)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Letter from Lydia, 1987 (Box 62, Folder 17)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Letter from Lydia, 5/7/1987 (Box 62, Folder 18)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Letter from Lydia and package wrapping, 7/1987 (Box 62, Folder 19)
    - Lydia Mendoza: letter from Lydia, 4/9/1988 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Money order from Ester to Lydia, with note from Lydia, 1988 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Lydia Mendoza; Note from Lydia and wrapping from her package to Ester, 1988 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Lydia Mendoza:Letter from Fred Martinez, re: Lydia's hospitalization, 1988 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Lydia Mendoza: 3 public relations photographs, photographer unknown. (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Lydia Mendoza: 2 photopraphs, autographed, photographer unknown, 5/22/1982, 523/1982 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Autographed photograph, dedicated to Ester, photographer unknown, 5/10/1985 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Autographed photograph, photographer and date unknown. (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Announcement for Mario Obledo campaign event, Lydia Mendoza entertaining, Oakland, CA, 5/22/1982 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Photocopied newspaper article regarding Lydia's artist in residency at Fresno State University, 1982 (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Autographed publicity photographs of Alexandra Valdiva, country and western singer and beautician, Fresno, CA, ca. 1982 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Photocopied newspaper article and announcement regarding Lydia's appearance at Wheeler Auditorium, UC Berkeley, 4/10/1982 (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Photocopied material from the Congressional Record, NY Times, SF Chronicle, etc. regarding Lydia's National Endowment for the Arts Heritage Award, 1982. (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Announcement and photographic proofs of Lydia's performance at San Juan Bautista, CA, Teatro Campesino, 5/22-23/1982 (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Performance at La Pena, Berkeley, CA: contract, announcements, 1985 (Box 63, Folder 15)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia's performance at Posada de Colores, Oakland CA, 1985: coorespondence, newspaper announcement (Box 63, Folder 16)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Postcard, layout,design, and finished cards, 1985. (Box 63, Folder 17)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Perfomance at Cinco de Mayo celebration, UC Berkeley, with Flaco Jimenez, 1985: flyers, poster, contracts, photographs (Box 63, Folder 18)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Miscellaneous material: receipts, schedules, etc. 1985 (Box 63, Folder 19)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Adal Maldonado "Avant Garde Mambo Society" photograph exhibit at Galeria de la Raza,. featuring photos of Latin American musicians, including Lydia Mendoza. Includes flyers, announcement, and correspondence, 1985. (Box 63, Folder 20)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia's performance at La Pena, Berkeley, CA, 1986, includes flyers, announcement, photograph. (Box 63, Folder 21)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia's performance at La Pena, Berkeley, CA, 1987, includes flyers, announcement, contract, etc. (Box 63, Folder 22)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Design by Ester Hernandez for publicity release, autographed by Lydia, 1987. (Box 63, Folder 23)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Sor Juana "Tribute to Women" Festival, Mexican Fine Art Center, Chicago, Lydia one of several honorees. Includes several drafts of Ester Hernandez's introductory speech, brochure, flyers, notes, etc., 1996. (Box 63, Folder 24)
    - Lydia Mendoza: miscellaneous brochures, flyers, etc. (Box 63, Folder 25)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Los Primeros Duetos Femininos: photocopied notes regarding early recordings of Texas-Mexican Border music, including Lydia Mendoza and the Mendoza family, authored by Phillip Sonnichsen. Also includes photocopies of catalog pages from Arhoolie Records, catalog from DownHome Music. (Box 63, Folder 26)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Chulas Fronteras: information regarding documentary produced by Brazos Film, featuring Lydia Mendoza. (Box 63, Folder 27)
    - Lydia Mendoza: photocopied miscellaneous reviews. (Box 63, Folder 28)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Interview with Ester Hernandez, discussing the difficulties of being a woman artist, Fresno, CA, 4/20/1981, audio cassette (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Interview with Ester Hernandez, discussing women artists, Fresno, CA, 1982 audio cassette (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Interview with Ester Hernandez, discussing Lydia's disability, future plans, Chicago, 10/19/90 audio cassette (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza, Big Star Records 7089, Rangel Record Distributors, San Antonio TX, 1989, audio cassette (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lidia Mendoza y Lorenzo Caballero: Por Primera Vez Juntos en una Grabacion, Gapoca Records, G.P. Records, Houston, TX, 1980, audio cassette (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza Con Corridos y Corridos, Norteno Records 822, n.d., audio cassette (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza - La Alondra de la Frontera, DLB Records 1139, San Antonio, TX, n.d. audio cassette (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza - La Alondra de la Frontera - Collecion de Oro, DLB Records 1094, San Antonio, TX, 1984[?]. audio cassette (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza - En Vivo desde New York, DLB Records 2000, San Antonio, TX, 1994, audio cassette. (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza - Toda Una Epoca, DLB Records 1113, San Antonio, TX, n.d., audio cassette (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lidia Mendoza, America Records, AIA029, n.d. audio cassette (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza, La Alondra de la Frontera, Norteno Records 809, n.d., 809 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Lydia Mendoza: KPFA interview: Chris Scrachwitz discusses Lydia Mendoza and the Mendoza Family History, 1987[1 of 2], audio cassette (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - Lydia Mendoza: KPFA interview: Chris Scrachwitz discusses Lydia Mendoza and the Mendoza Family History, 1987[2 of 2], audio cassette (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - Lydia Mendoza: KPFA - Tejano Music Retrospective - featuring Lydia Mendoza in interview and live performance, 1988, audio cassette (Box 64, Folder 15)
    - Lydia Mendoza: KPFA - Jesse "Chuy" Barela interviews Tex/Mex singer Freddie Fender, Lydia Mendoza mentioned as an influence on him and other musicians, ca. 1988, audio cassette (Box 64, Folder 16)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza recorded live at La Pena Cultural Center, Berkeley, CA, 9/16/1986 [1 of 2] audio cassette (Box 64, Folder 17)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza recorded live at La Pena Cultural Center, Berkeley, CA, 9/16/1986 [2 of 2] audio cassette (Box 64, Folder 18)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza: Mas exitos de "La Alondra de la Frontera," source tape Falcon FLP-2029 [Side A]; La Alondra de la Frontera, no source noted [Side B], audio cassette (Box 64, Folder 19)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza: En Tu Dia, source Corona CLP 3003 [Side A]; Lydia Mendoza con su Guitarra, source tape Azteca 8012 (Box 64, Folder 20)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza: La Alondra de la Frontera con el Mariachi Aguila, source tape Paloma 1011 [Side A] (Box 64, Folder 21)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza interviewed by Ester Hernandez, Sor Juana Festival, Mexican Museum Art Center, Chicago. Renee Moreno, videographer, 1996, VHS cassette (Box 64, Folder 22)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza, La Alondra de la Frontera y Su Guitarra de Oro: 50 anos, DLP Records #1094, LP (Box 65, Folder 1)
      Cover autographed and inscribed
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza y Su Guitarra de Oro, La Alondra de la Frontera, Norteno Records #812, LP (Box 65, Folder 2)
      Back cover autographed and inscribed
    - Lydia Mendoza: La Alondra de la Frontera - Lydia Mendoza y Su Guitarra con Beto Villa, Mariachi Ideal, and Narciso Martinez, Ideal Records #120, LP (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Dueto Monterrey con Guitarras, Azteca Records #AM 8011, LP (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Que hare tan sola - Lydia Mendoza canta sus Composiciones con su Guitarra, Azteca Records #AM 8017, LP (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza con su Guitarra, Una Voz Y Una Guitarra, Azteca Records # AM 8030, LP (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza Part 1: First Recordings, 1928-1938, Una historia de la musica de la frontera, Texas-Mexican Border Music vol 15, Folklyric Records #9023, LP (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza Part 2: Early Recordings, from the 1930s, Una historia de la musica de la frontera, Texas-Mexican Border Music vol 16, Folklyric Records #9024, LP (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza - La Gloria de Texas, Arhoolie Records # 3012, LP (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Lydia Mendoza - La Alondra de la Frontera, con el Mariachi Aguila, Paloma Records # 1011 (Box 65, Folder 10)
      Jacket only, no LP
    - Lydia Mendoza: Black velvet dress with colored sequins in floral pattern (Box 66)
      Worn for filming of "Chulas Fronteras," ca. 1960s
    - Lydia Mendoza: Rebozo, lime-green with red striping, black and white patterns, worn with "Adelita Dress,"ca. 1960s (Box 67)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Hand-made dress for musical performance, white with red and blue stripes, white lace trimming, the "Adelita Dress," ca. 1960s (Box 67)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Hand-made blue satin dress with yellow ribbon, white rickrack, and lace trim, ca. 1960s (Box 68)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Mask of Lydia Mendoza's face, created by Ester Hernandez of white plaster and gauze, ca. 1988 (Box 69)
    - Lydia Mendoza: Miscellaneous personal items collected by Ester Hernandez during Lydia's to Oakland. (Box 70)
      Jewelry, hair ornaments, styrofoam "head" for wig, cosmetics, pillowcase and face towel with traces of Lydia's makeup makeup, beer can with lipstick impression, other miscellaneous items
  - Selena, Subseries 6.5
    - Tres Flores: Lydia, Astrid, y Selena, lecture Stanford University, 5/4/1999 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Selena: photocopied news articles regarding her murder and funeral, April 1995 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Selena article, US Magazine, March, 1996 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Selena Tribute, People Magazine special issue, Spring 1995 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Selena trubutes at San Jose Flea Market, 1999: postcard announcements (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Selena videotape, 1995 (Box 60, Folder 18)
  - Alice Walker, Subseries 6.6
    - Defiant Eyes exhibit photographs, 1988 (Box 72.1, Folder 1)
      Ester working on floral painting; Alice and Ester together at unidentified gathering
    - Photographs, slides (Box 72.1, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous greeting cards, invitations, etc. (Box 72.1, Folder 3)
    - Directions and instructions for Walker's Casa Careyes House, Mexico. (Box 72.1, Folder 4)
    - Alice Walker Calendar, 1986 (Box 72.1, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous book receptions, film opening, flyers (Box 72.1, Folder 6)
    - Bill of sale, canceled checks, thank you notes (Box 72.1, Folder 7)
    - Robert Allen's (Alice's companion) astrology chart, ca. 1988 (Box 72.1, Folder 8)
    - Adam [?] rough draft, ca. 1992 (Box 72.1, Folder 9)
    - This is the House That Charlie Built: work in progress, 1990 (Box 72.1, Folder 10)
    - Stationery and envelopes from Steiner House, and Wild Tree Press (Box 72.1, Folder 11)
    - Nightmare Begins Responsibility, press conference, SF City Hall, 12/6/1989 (Box 72.1, Folder 12)
    - Magic Potion information for use in a new house, ca. 1991 (Box 72.1, Folder 13)
    - Birth date information [in Alice Walker's hand] (Box 72.1, Folder 14)
    - Water color collaboration with Ester, ca. 1991 (Box 72.1, Folder 15)
    - Sketches by Ester of Alice's house in Navarro, CA, ca. 1991 (Box 72.1, Folder 16)
    - Logo project for Our Daughters Have Mothers, Inc., 1993 (Box 72.1, Folder 17)
    - Notes regarding logo project for Our Daughters Have Mothers, Inc., 1993 (Box 72.2, Folder 1)
    - Turquoise and Coral Moon, draft (Temple of my Familiar, for SF Chronicle Book Review, 5/7/1989 (Box 72.2, Folder 2)
    - Lead quote on "The Art of Provocation: Ester Hernandez," exhibit publication, 1995 (Box 72.2, Folder 3)
    - Greeting cards produced by Wild Trees Press (Box 72.2, Folder 4)
    - Alice Walker: phone messages, audio cassette, 1990 (Box 72.2, Folder 5)
- Public Relations, Series 7; 1 linear ft.
  Series 7 contains various announcements, news articles, exhibit catalogs, brochures, etc. concerning the display or discussion of Hernandez's work.
  - Mexican Museum Folio, 1997 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Oakland Museum: Traditions of Transformation (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - "Valley Grown:" Mexican American Visions and Voices from the Central Valley, 1998 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - "Transformations: The Art of Ester Hernandez," Artweek, 1998 (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - Transformations: The Art of Ester Hernandez, Catalog, 1998 (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - Posters American Style (Box 71, Folder 11)
  - Experimental Texts...Other Authors...Other Forms, 1997 (Box 71, Folder 12)
  - "Exploring the Breadth of Hispanic Art Today:" NY Times, Aug 27, 1996 (Box 71, Folder 13)
  - Sor Juana Festival, Chicago, 1995 (Box 71, Folder 14)